# Onni Kosomaa

onni.kosomaa@gmail.com | +358 45 8965899 | Helsinki, Finland https://kosomon.github.io/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/onnikosomaa/

#### **ABOUT ME**

I'm a driven and proactive engineer with extensive professional experience within software engineering and machine learning research. Before transferring back to automotive software engineering, I spent several years developing a novel deep learning method for 3D medical imaging reconstruction. I have a no-fuss approach to all my work, and I strive to solve problems from a practical standpoint while maintaining a solid theoretical foundation. I have experience in low-level development with rigorous testing and safety standards. I'm used to balancing performance, safety and code quality. My electrical engineering education has given me a strong background in signal processing, hardware knowledge, and low-level systems and embedded programming.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Compute Software Engineer, Basemark**

Dec 2022 -

- I'm developing a safety critical GPU compute engine, focused on neural network inference for nextgeneration automotive augmented reality applications.
- I optimize GPU kernels, improve functional safety and author documentation.
- C++, Vulkan SC, GLSL, Python.

#### Research Staff, Aalto University & NVIDIA

Feb 2021 - Nov 2022

- I developed a fully three-dimensional CT reconstruction algorithm using deep learning, based on the first principles of digital signal processing.
- Publication Self-Supervised Deep Learning for Volumetric Helical CT Reconstruction in review as of Nov 2022.
- My work led to two patent applications in July 2021.
- I designed and wrote all the software used.
- Additionally, I developed differentiable alias-free versions of commonly used tomographic primitive operations as well as a 3D CT volume renderer for visualizing the results, using CUDA and OpenGL.
- Technologies utilized were Python, CUDA, C++, PyTorch, DICOM.
- Extreme memory consumption of volumetric deep learning pipeline required adding several custom CUDA operations to the PyTorch implementation, and optimization of GPU memory bandwidth was crucial.

#### **Research Scientist, NVIDIA**

May 2020 - Jan 2021

I researched deep learning for CT reconstruction. My bachelor's thesis is based on this research.

# System Software Engineer, NVIDIA

Sep 2019 - Apr 2020

- I worked on automotive ISO 26262 ASIL-B safety certification and development of a Linux user space GPU driver for the Tegra SoC, while also developing new features for upcoming chips.
- Additionally, I wrote design documents, refactored code to adhere to safety standards, and increased testing coverage.
- Codebase was C++17 run on SoCs, and Python for scripting. Coding standards MISRA and AUTOSAR C++.
- I received "Top Contributor" status, awarded amongst top 5% of engineers of matching seniority level.
- Additionally, four internships within System Software Engineering at NVIDIA, totaling 14 months.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

# **Projection-Domain Self-Supervision for Volumetric Helical CT Reconstruction**

In review as of January 2023. Pre-print available at the project page.

Onni Kosomaa, Samuli Laine, Tero Karras, Miika Aittala, Jaakko Lehtinen.

## End-to-end training for a three-dimensional tomography reconstruction pipeline

Patent US17/365,574 - Filed Jul 1, 2021

Onni Kosomaa, Jaakko Lehtinen, Samuli Laine, Tero Karras, Miika Aittala.

## Three-dimensional tomography reconstruction pipeline

Patent US17/365,645 - Filed Jul 1, 2021

Onni Kosomaa, Jaakko Lehtinen, Samuli Laine, Tero Karras, Miika Aittala.

### **EDUCATION**

Aalto University Sep 2016 – Dec 2020

BSc with Honors, Electrical Engineering. Top one university in Finland.

- 4.6/5.0 GPA (EE Major: 4.7/5.0, CS Minor: 5.0/5.0)
- Absent for conscript service during Fall 2017 Spring 2018

## **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

- Skills:
  - Modern C++, C, and Python.
  - CUDA, Vulkan, PyTorch, OpenGL, Linux, Git.
  - Functional safety, GPU compute, deep learning, computer vision, embedded systems.
  - Native speaker of Finnish and Swedish, fluent in English.
- Interests: Woodworking, cooking, bouldering, and restoring old furniture and electronics.